Alessandra Maccario **UX/UI** Designer

I am a UX/UI designer with 10+ years experience in the field and I am currently open to new opportunities to lend my skills to helpful, engaging and innovative digital products.

In my previous roles I was described as a resilient, reliable, and altruistic natural leader. I have an inquisitive personality and I am a great listener as I love learning about how people think, what drives their motivation and why they act the way they do.

My constant need to improve myself pushes me to put my learnings into practice every day getting out from my confort zone.

I considering myself a very creative person who finds inspiration from everyday things like music, art or all the small things I can observe in the streets during my commuting time.

I strongly believe in the power of simplicity and in the need to put customers in the center of what we do. Therefore I am an advocate of design thinking and agile methodology.

- A genuine willingness to help clients to solve problems and find solutions
- Empathy / Emotional intelligence
- A good listener with ability to understand what clients need





London, UK alessandra.maccario@gmail.com +44 751 777 4527

www.alessandramaccario.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alessandra-maccario

Skills

- Visual Design
- Graphic Design
- Responsive Web Design
- Mobile Application
- Interaction Design
- Wirefraiming
- Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- Sketching & Ideation
- UX Strategy
- Information Architecture
- User Research
- Digital Designer
- Web Designer
- Leadership, communication and teamwork
- Project Management
- Brand Guidelines

Languages 🗸

- English
- Italian (native)

Tools

- Pen and Paper
- Agile Methodology
- Jira
- Zeplin
- Abstract
- Zeroheight
- Sketch
- InVision
- XD
- Figma
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign
- Html
- Dreamweaver/ CSS
- Keynote
- Canvas
- Google slide
- Microsoft office

Experience

Senior UX/ UI Design Investis Digital 2020 to date

My current role at Investis Digital is as a Senior UX/UI Designer, helping our design team understand our client's needs, developing unique digital concepts for established brands, and mentoring our junior members of the group.

Through my commitment to this role, I helped Investis Digital improve its core UX service and shape digital real-estates for companies like GSK, Vifor Pharma, JTI, Caretech, Owen Mumford, Mundipharma, Vodafone, and much more.

Currently I am a UX/Visual consultant for our strategic accounts.

Freelance Designer 2015 to date

UX/ UI Fashion, web, graphic design and marketing campaigns; personal portfolio: www.alessandramaccario.com

Before joining the Investis Digital team, I was a Freelancer Senior Designer. I was at the front of creating unique digital experiences for start-ups within a smaller digital agency. The role was challenging but it gave me a unique perspective on how to reach a company's digital communication goals.

UX/ UI designer at Flatiron School

June 2019 to Dec 2019

During this six-month intensive course, I could practise new skills while working directly with the client. Bambinista is an online fashion boutique focusing on ethically produced and sustainably manufactured clothing, accessories and toys for kids aged 0-6 years. In collaboration with my team, I re-designed the branding, UX and UI concepts as part of Bambinista's upcoming website restyle.

Educational History

English Course "Reading well, Writing well" ESOL LEVEL 2 City Lit School London 2018

Post – Master in Advertising, Art Director and Copy Second Degree Level, ILAS, Naples, Italy, 2010

Certificate in Adobe Dreamweaver CS 4 and Flash CS 4, ILAS, Naples,

Graphic Designer Academy of Art, Rome, Italy 2001 – 2005

Interests



- Painting
- Music
- Movie
- Art & Theatre
- Drawing & Sketching
- Cooking